<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="B7AB1949-CE90-4289-A32D-3049187EF0A7">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120524" date="2012-05-25 01:55:33 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Vendors</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="10_Vendors_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="395px" height="210px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Educators and trainers are often faced with a question from students regarding possible roles in an enterprise for software assurance professionals and their demand in the workforce. To facilitate such discussion, we have collected a few quotes from several training and credentialing entities below.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;SANS&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The SANS Software Security Institute (SSI) brings computer security training to developers, programmers, and application security professionals. They offer training for web application security and hacking defense, secure coding, software security testing, code review, PCI compliance, and language specific training for Java/JEE, .NET, C, and others. They also offer the Programmer/Developer Certification (GSSP) through their GIAC affiliate. They are also a source of free resources such as the Top 25 Most Dangerous Programming Errors. According to the System Administration, Audit, Network Security (SANS) Institute, one of the Top 20 coolest careers is Security-Savvy.&#xD;&#xD;Software Developer:&#xD;The security-savvy software developer leads all developers in the creation of secure software, implementing secure programming techniques that are free from logical design and technical implementation flaws.  This expert is ultimately responsible for ensuring customer software is free from vulnerabilities that can be exploited by an attacker.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Why It's Cool&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;    "You get to make something that actually runs and does something (and won't break under pressure)."&#xD;    "These guys are the senior developers by virtue of their programming prowess."&#xD;&lt;b&gt;How It Makes a Difference&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;    "No security architecture or policy can compensate for poorly written, buggy, insecure software.  &#xD;    If one pays the necessary attention to security when a product is initially developed, one doesn't &#xD;    need to go back and add security later on."&#xD;    "This is where the rubber meets the road.  These are the people making a difference where &#xD;    it really matters...in the software that runs the world."&#xD;&lt;b&gt;How to Be Successful&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The role of security-savvy software developer is challenging and rewarding from multiple perspectives.  To be successful, you must understand a multitude of attack vectors used to exploit software to avoid the introduction of flaws.  This experience is also needed to leverage the same attack tools and techniques an adversary might use to exploit your software, and identify flaws to be addressed before product shipment. In a development role, your position will be vital to the company's success, including your ability to communicate the techniques used for secure software development to your peers.  This can be challenging, since few enjoy having their work criticized and flaws identified, but is a necessary component of an overall secure software strategy.  This role is critical beyond the success of the company to that of all the customers who implement your software.  Secure software development has a direct and undeniable impact on the ability of an organization to protect their systems and information assets, and you play a key role in that success.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;EC-Council&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The International Council of E-Commerce Consultants (EC-Council) is a member-based organization that certifies individuals in various e-business and information security skills. It is the owner and developer of the Certified Ethical Hacker (C|EH), Computer Hacking Forensics Investigator (C|HFI), and EC-Council Certified Security Analyst (E|CSA)/License Penetration Tester (L|PT) programs, and various others offered in over 60 countries around the globe. EC-Council is the creator of the Hacker Halted conference and workshop series and has established the EC-Council University based in New Mexico, which offers both bachelor's and master's degree programs. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Why Secure Programming&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;    Most vulnerabilities stem from a relatively small number of common programming errors, according to the CERT/CC vulnerability reports. Understanding the security vulnerabilities in the application allows designers to create better security strategies for the application. The pervasiveness of easily remedied vulnerabilities indicates a lack of developer education on secure coding - VERACODE. Security quality of software ultimately determines the rate of data breaches and cyber threats that result in substantial losses to an organization.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Reduce costs:&lt;/b&gt; The relative cost of fixing software defects after deployment is almost 15 times greater than detecting and eliminating them during development, according to a study by IBM's System Sciences Institute. &#xD;&lt;b&gt;Reduce serious risks: &lt;/b&gt;Despite having mission-critical applications accessible via their websites, many organizations are failing to provide sufficient resources to secure and protect Web applications important to their operations, according to the survey &#x2018;State of Web Application &#xD;&lt;b&gt;Everyone benefits: &lt;/b&gt;Secure applications are more protected from media criticism, more attractive to users, and less expensive to fix and support.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;How to Be a Successful Secure Programmer?&#xD;Understand the adversary: &lt;/b&gt;Just as a law officer uses &#x201C;criminal profiling&#x201D; to recognize the characteristics of unknown criminals, the successful secure programmer understands all the facets and the attack vectors a cyber-criminal may use to exploit the vulnerabilities in a software code. &#xD;&lt;b&gt;Avoid training gaps:&lt;/b&gt; Most application developers do not have any formal training in secure coding. Programming education curriculums most often do not include security issues. This results in developers who are either not aware of security issues or poorly skilled to overcome these issues. &#xD;&lt;b&gt;Invigorate security topics: &lt;/b&gt;The teaching methodology used by educational and training centers contributes to the erroneous perception of security topics as a dull subject.  Incorporating the development and procurement of resilient software and systems throughout the lifespan of a project relies on developer interest&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Work from a solid base:&lt;/b&gt; Define security and privacy requirements at the beginning and require team members to understand the software development lifecycle thoroughly. Details about recommended courses can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.eccouncil.org/certification.aspx"&gt;http://www.eccouncil.org/certification.aspx&lt;/a&gt;. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;(ISC)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;International Information Systems Security Certification Consortium, Inc., (ISC)&#xB2;&#xAE; (pronounced "ISC-squared") is a non-profit organization that educates and certifies information security professionals throughout their careers. The most widely known certification offered by the organization is the Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP). The Certified Secure Software Lifecycle Professional (CSSLP) Certification Program shows software lifecycle stakeholders how to implement security and how to glean security requirements, design, architect, test, and deploy secure software.  Attendees of the Software Assurance Forums and Working Group Sessions can receive "Continuing Professional Education&#x201D; (CPE) credits.&#xD;&#xD;The (ISC)2&#xAE;  CSSLP&#xAE; Curriculum  is a blueprint for establishing a security initiative in the software development lifecycle (SDLC).  It provides clear policies, procedures, and best practices for applying the NIST, PCI-DSS, and ISO 27xx standards.  Additionally, it incorporates best practices, policies, and procedures from Symantec, Cisco, Microsoft, SRA International, Xerox, EMC2, SAFEcode, SANS, RSA, ISSA, and The Department of Homeland Security. &#xD;The comprehensive (ISC)2&#xAE; CSSLP&#xAE; CBK&#xAE; Education Program covers the following domains:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Secure Software Concepts&lt;/b&gt; - security implications and methodologies within centralized and decentralized environments across the enterprise&#x2019;s computer systems in software development.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Secure Software Requirements&lt;/b&gt; - capturing security controls used during the requirements phase to integrate security within the process, to identify key security objectives, and to maximize software security while minimizing disruption to plans and schedules.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Secure Software Design&lt;/b&gt; - translating security requirements into application design elements including documenting the elements of the software attack surfaces, conducting threat modeling, and defining any specific security criteria.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Secure Software Implementation/Coding&lt;/b&gt; - involves the application of coding and testing standards, applying security testing tools including &#x2018;fuzzing&#x2019;, static-analysis code scanning tools, and conducting code reviews.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Secure Software Testing&lt;/b&gt; - integrated QA testing for security functionality and resiliency to attack.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Software Acceptance&lt;/b&gt; - security implications in the software acceptance phase including completion criteria, risk acceptance and documentation, Common Criteria and methods of independent testing.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Software Deployment, Operations, Maintenance and Disposal &lt;/b&gt;- security issues around steady state operations and management of software. Security measures that must be taken when a product reaches its end of life.&#xD;&#xD;RESOURCES&#xD;&#xD;System Administration, Audit, Network Security (SANS). Details about recommended courses can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.sans.org/20coolestcareers/#job18"&gt;http://www.sans.org/20coolestcareers/#job18&lt;/a&gt;.  &#xD;&#xD;State of Web Application Security conducted by Ponemon Institute and sponsored by Imperva &amp; WhiteHat Security, published April 26, 2010.&#xD;&#xD;The (ISC)&#xB2; Resource Guide for Information Security Professional, latest educational references, event listings, and leading industry organizations.https://&lt;a href="http://www.isc2.org/resourceguide/"&gt;www.isc2.org/resourceguide/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;The CSSLP Education Program, &lt;a href="http://www.isc2.org/csslpedu"&gt;www.isc2.org/csslpedu&lt;/a&gt;&#xD; &#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Vendors</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;4/10/12&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
