<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="B7AB1949-CE90-4289-A32D-3049187EF0A7">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120524" date="2012-05-25 01:55:31 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Strategy</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="3_Injecting_SwA_topics_in_current_programs_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="395px" height="210px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>A enumeration of strategies to integrate software assurance topics into current education and training programs &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Publications on this topic&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Crosstalk March/April 2012, Carol A. Sledge, Engaging the Community: Strategies for Software Assurance Curricula Outreach.&#xD;Engaging a knowledgeable team of educators to develop curricula, courses, and other materials for the discipline of software assurance will achieve more secure and better functioning software systems, regardless of their origins, application domain, or operational environments.&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.crosstalkonline.org/storage/issue-archives/2012/201203/201203-Sledge.pdf"&gt;http://www.crosstalkonline.org/storage/issue-archives/2012/201203/201203-Sledge.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Degree programs and specializations in SwA&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Reference curriculums available from the Software Engineering Institute, Carnegie Mellon University can be used as recommendations for designing Masters of Software Assurance degree program and undergraduate curriculum specialization in software assurance. These reference curriculums are available at&#xD;&lt;a href="http://repository.cmu.edu/sei/3/"&gt;http://repository.cmu.edu/sei/3/&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://repository.cmu.edu/sei/4/"&gt;http://repository.cmu.edu/sei/4/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Graduate Certificates and Master Degree Concentrations at the Stevens Institute of Technology: &lt;a href="http://dc.stevens.edu/academic-programs/software-assurance/"&gt;http://dc.stevens.edu/academic-programs/software-assurance/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Stand-alone Courses	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;New course offerings based on SwA knowledge areas complement existing Software Engineering courses. Examples: &lt;a href="http://www.cs.jmu.edu/sss"&gt;http://www.cs.jmu.edu/sss&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&lt;a href="https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/display/sci/S08+15392+Secure+Programming"&gt;https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/display/sci/S08+15392+Secure+Programming&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Also: graduate-level Software Assurance courses that cover secure software engineering activities during the SDLC are offered at the University of North Carolina at Charlotte, and The University of Nebraska at Omaha.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Augmenting Existing Courses	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The SwA CBK and State-of-the-Art reports are catalogs of secure software development practices, processes, and techniques that can be mapped to topics relevant to current curriculums. The identified gaps can then be filled using relevant materials.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Micro-Modules	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Problem-based learning exercises, in class workshops, or short talks to inject topics such as Misuse Cases and Assurance Cases into existing software engineering or information security courses. Several other topics can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.cert.org/mswa/lectures.html"&gt;http://www.cert.org/mswa/lectures.html&lt;/a&gt; &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Capstone and Class Projects	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Software Engineering capstone courses or class projects which can be geared towards a security critical domain such as designing a software system for the Department of Defense, Cyber-physical systems or for a Credit Card transaction processing company.  These domains will facilitate the exploration of security needs throughout the SDLC.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Online Courses	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The Adaptive Cyber-Security Training Online (ACT-Online) courses are available on the TEEX Domestic Preparedness Campus. Ten courses address three discipline- specific tracks.  The targets are everyday non-technical computer users, technical IT professionals, business managers and professionals.  These courses are offered at no cost and students earn a DHS/FEMA Certificate of completion along with Continuing Education Units (CEU) at the completion of each course.        &#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.teexwmdcampus.com/user_defined_content.k2?contentID=6"&gt;http://www.teexwmdcampus.com/user_defined_content.k2?contentID=6&lt;/a&gt; &#xD;&#xD;The CERT Virtual Training Environment (VTE) combines the components of traditional classroom training with the convenience of web-based training.  Over 200 hours of course material focused around the technical, policy, and management implications of information security &#x2013; including preparatory courses for commercial certifications, core skills courses, role-based courses for managers and technical staff, and vendor-developed courses. Open access is provided to individual DoD personnel (Active Duty, DoD Civilian and contractors) and members of the Federal Civilian Workforce through specific sponsorships from DISA, and DHS in conjunction with the Department of State Foreign Service Institute.  Sponsored accounts can be requested at &lt;a href="http://www.vte.cert.org"&gt;www.vte.cert.org&lt;/a&gt;.  Public access to many of the materials is provided through the VTE Library at &lt;a href="https://www.vte.cert.org/vteweb/Library/Library.aspx"&gt;https://www.vte.cert.org/vteweb/Library/Library.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Semantic Templates	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;To cope with growing software complexity, programmers need better mental models to sense the possibility of a weakness. Current weakness enumerations and categorizations are not in a form that facilitates programmer understanding and recall. Semantic templates are being developed at the University of Nebraska, Omaha to improve programmer's ability to understand the CWEs related to the underlying software faults, weakness characteristics, resources/locations affected and the consequences for various egregious weakness types. &lt;a href="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/st/"&gt;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/st/&lt;/a&gt; &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Software Fault Patterns	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Software Fault Patterns (SFP) provide a generalized description of an identifiable family of computations that lead to weaknesses. These patterns are aligned with CWEs and are fully identifiable in code. &#xD;&lt;a href="https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/presentations_091211/Mansourov-SoftwareFaultPatterns.pdf"&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/presentations_091211/Mansourov-SoftwareFaultPatterns.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Awareness and Self-study Resources	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;SAFECode: Software Assurance Forum for Excellence in Code. &lt;a href="http://www.safecode.org"&gt;http://www.safecode.org&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Fundamental Practices for Secure Software Development&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Dev_Practices1108.pdf"&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Dev_Practices1108.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Security Engineering Training&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Training0409.pdf"&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Training0409.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Software Assurance: An Overview of Current Industry Best Practices&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_BestPractices0208.pdf"&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_BestPractices0208.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Framework for Software Supply Chain Integrity&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Supply_Chain0709.pdf"&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Supply_Chain0709.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Software Integrity Controls: An Assurance-Based Approach to Minimizing Risks in the Software Supply Chain. &lt;a href="http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Software_Integrity_Controls0610.pdf"&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Software_Integrity_Controls0610.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;Rugged Software&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.ruggedsoftware.org"&gt;http://www.ruggedsoftware.org&lt;/a&gt;/&#xD;&#xD;Podcasts&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.cigital.com/silverbullet/"&gt;http://www.cigital.com/silverbullet/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Community Support&lt;/b&gt;	&#xD;LinkedIn SwA Education Discussion Group&#xD;Nancy Mead, SwA Curriculum Team lead&#xD;The objective of the SwA Curriculum Development Team in establishing this group is to provide a venue for dialog about software assurance education. &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/groups?mostPopular=&amp;gid=3430456"&gt;http://www.linkedin.com/groups?mostPopular=&amp;gid=3430456&lt;/a&gt;&#xD; &#xD;Software Assurance Mobile Instructional (device) SAMI&#xD;Dan Shoemaker, University of Detroit Mercy&#xD;A catalogue of available software assurance materials that are packaged and delivered using an iPad based instruction medium for educators.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Credentialing&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;Several certification options are now available to suit the needs of specific job functions required in an enterprise. More information can be found in the Workforce Credentials article.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Injecting SwA topics in current programs</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;4/3/12&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
