<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="B7AB1949-CE90-4289-A32D-3049187EF0A7">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120524" date="2012-05-25 01:55:32 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Standards of Practice</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="6_Standards_of_practice_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="395px" height="210px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Domain-specific Software Assurance standards used in practice&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Assurance Process Reference Model (PRM)	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Presentation: &lt;a href="https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/downloads/ACSAC2010BartolMoss12-05-2010.pdf"&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/downloads/ACSAC2010BartolMoss12-05-2010.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Self Assessment: &lt;a href="https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/downloads/20100922_PRM_Practice_List_2page.pdf"&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/downloads/20100922_PRM_Practice_List_2page.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;The Assurance PRM can be used to help organizations conduct a gap analysis of existing practices. The results of a gap analysis can be used to prioritize and track SwA implementation efforts. The Assurance PRM addresses assurance from executive to developer.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;BSIMM: The Building Security In Maturity Model&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://bsimm2.com"&gt;http://bsimm.com&lt;/a&gt;/&#xD;Pronounced &#x201C;bee simm&#x201D; was created by observing and analyzing real-world data from thirty leading software security initiatives. The BSIMM can help you determine how your organization compares to other real-world software security initiatives and what steps can be taken to make your approach more effective.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;CERT Resilience Management Model&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cert.org/resilience/rmm.html"&gt;http://www.cert.org/resilience/rmm.html&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;It has two primary objectives:&#xD;1. Establish the convergence of operational risk and resilience management activities such as security, business continuity, and aspects of IT operations management into a single model.&#xD;2. Apply a process improvement approach to operational resilience management through the definition and application of a capability level scale that expresses increasing levels of process improvement.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;CMMI-ACQ: Carnegie Mellon University (CMU)/Software Engineering Institute (SEI) Capability Maturity Model Integration (CMMI) for Acquisitions	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sei.cmu.edu/cmmi/index.cfm"&gt;http://www.sei.cmu.edu/cmmi/index.cfm&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Version 1.2. CMMI for Acquisition (CMMI-ACQ) is based on the CMMI Framework. CMMI for Acquisition (CMMI-ACQ) provides guidance to acquisition organizations for initiating and managing the acquisition of products and services. The model focuses on acquirer processes and integrates bodies of knowledge that are essential for successful acquisitions.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;MISRA C: Motor Industry Software Reliability Association (MISRA)	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.misra.org.uk"&gt;http://www.misra.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;/&#xD;A software development standard for the C programming language developed by MISRA. Its aims are to facilitate code safety, portability and reliability in the context of embedded systems, specifically those systems programmed in ISO C. There is also a set of guidelines for MISRA C++.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;openSAMM: OWASP Open Software Assurance Maturity Model &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.opensamm.org"&gt;http://www.opensamm.org&lt;/a&gt;/&#xD;An open framework to help organizations formulate and implement a strategy for software security that is tailored to the specific risks facing the organization.&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Standards of practice</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;4/6/12&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
