<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Topics</title>
    <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Topics.html</link>
    <description>This Web Guide focuses on enumerating education, training and certification resources.  It identifies the most effective strategies to inject software assurance topics into existing college curriculums and workforce training and certification programs.</description>
    <generator>iWeb 3.0.4</generator>
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/13_News.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">a4e93cb9-4670-4f2c-a8cf-8a4c70f43b2c</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 12:36:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/13_News_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object085_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;DHS/FEMA Certified Cyber Security Training Courses offered at no cost online&lt;br/&gt;10 online courses in 3 discipline-specific tracks for end-users, IT professionals and managers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teexwmdcampus.com/user_defined_content.k2?contentID=6&quot;&gt;http://www.teexwmdcampus.com/user_defined_content.k2?contentID=6&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;IEEE Guide to the Software Engineering Body of Knowledge—SWEBOK&lt;br/&gt;Refresh is currently under way.&lt;br/&gt;To contribute to this effort and more information visit:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://computer.centraldesktop.com/swebokv3review/&quot;&gt;http://computer.centraldesktop.com/swebokv3review/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Three knowledge areas are currently available for public review:&lt;br/&gt;Software Engineering Models and Methods&lt;br/&gt;Software Maintenance&lt;br/&gt;Mathematical Foundations&lt;br/&gt;Three knowledge areas have completed public review:&lt;br/&gt;Software Construction&lt;br/&gt;Software Configuration Management&lt;br/&gt;Computing Foundations&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;NICE cybersecurity workforce framework &lt;br/&gt;An effort to consistently describe cybersecurity workforce knowledge, skills and abilities. There is opportunity to review and provide feedback.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://csrc.nist.gov/nice/framework/&quot;&gt;http://csrc.nist.gov/nice/framework/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;NIST SP 800-53 Rev. 4 &lt;br/&gt;DRAFT Security and Privacy Controls for Federal Information Systems and Organizations &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/PubsDrafts.html&quot;&gt;http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/PubsDrafts.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Primary changes include controls for privacy and inclusion of SCAP and related standards.</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/13_News_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="15954" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal R&amp;D Opportunities</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/12_Federal_R%26D_Opportunities.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6bfab2af-561c-4aa1-bac5-07212a6d7042</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 09:46:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/12_Federal_R%26D_Opportunities_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object086_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cyber Security Research and Development Center&lt;br/&gt;The Cyber Security R&amp;amp;D Center was established by the Department of Homeland Security in 2004 to develop security technology for protection of the U.S. cyber infrastructure. The Center conducts its work through partnerships between government and private industry, the venture capital community, and the research community. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyber.st.dhs.gov/&quot;&gt;http://www.cyber.st.dhs.gov&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Trustworthy Cyberspace: Strategic Plan for the Federal Cybersecurity Research and Development Program&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyber.st.dhs.gov/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Fed_Cybersecurity_RD_Strategic_Plan_2011.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.cyber.st.dhs.gov/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Fed_Cybersecurity_RD_Strategic_Plan_2011.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Topics for Inducing change:&lt;br/&gt;    Designed-in Security&lt;br/&gt;    Tailored Trustworthy Spaces&lt;br/&gt;    Moving Target&lt;br/&gt;    Cyber Economic Incentives&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/12_Federal_R%26D_Opportunities_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="35194" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Academic and Commercial Training Samples </title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/11_Academic_and_Commercial_Training_Samples.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">61e5982f-6509-49f7-8d8b-1740057b1408</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 06:00:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/11_Academic_and_Commercial_Training_Samples_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object125_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A list of SwA education and training samples from academia and private organizations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Academic Curricula Samples&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/wetwgdocs.html&quot;&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/wetwgdocs.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Carnegie Mellon University CS curriculum &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csd.cs.cmu.edu/education/bscs/index.html#curriculum&quot;&gt;http://www.csd.cs.cmu.edu/education/bscs/index.html#curriculum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;George Washington University CS curriculum &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.ucdavis.edu/courses/exp_course_desc/index.html&quot;&gt;http://www.cs.ucdavis.edu/courses/exp_course_desc/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Massachusetts Institute of Technology EECS Undergraduate Program &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eecs.mit.edu/ug/index.html&quot;&gt;http://www.eecs.mit.edu/ug/index.html&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Master's program in Secure Software Systems at James Madison University &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.jmu.edu/sss/&quot;&gt;http://www.cs.jmu.edu/sss/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Stevens Institute of Technology, Software Assurance Program&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sse.stevens.edu/academics/graduate/software-engineering/program-overview/software-assurance/&quot;&gt;http://sse.stevens.edu/academics/graduate/software-engineering/program-overview/software-assurance/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Stanford University CS curriculum &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cs.stanford.edu/Courses/&quot;&gt;http://cs.stanford.edu/Courses/&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;University of California at Davis CS curriculum &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.ucdavis.edu/courses/exp_course_desc/index.html&quot;&gt;http://www.cs.ucdavis.edu/courses/exp_course_desc/index.html&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Commercial Training Examples&lt;br/&gt;Aspect Security, Inc., Application Security Education and Training &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aspectsecurity.com/training.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.aspectsecurity.com/training.htm&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;EC-Council, Application and Information Security, and Computer Forensic Investigation Training &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eccouncil.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.eccouncil.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;EC-Council University Master of Security Science (MSS) &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eccuni.us/Academics/MasterofSecurityScience.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.eccuni.us/Academics/MasterofSecurityScience.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Foundstone, Inc., Education&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foundstone.com/us/education-overview.asp&quot;&gt;http://www.foundstone.com/us/education-overview.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;KRvW Associates, LLC., Training Services&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.krvw.com/training/training.html&quot;&gt;http://www.krvw.com/training/training.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;LogiGear, Inc., Web and Software Application Security Testing &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.logigear.com/training/course_catalog/course.asp?courseId=20&quot;&gt;http://www.logigear.com/training/course_catalog/course.asp?courseId=20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Microsoft Corp., Clinic 2806: Microsoft® Security Guidance Training for Developers (and other courses)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoftelearning.com/eLearning/courseDetail.aspx?courseId=26043&quot;&gt;https://www.microsoftelearning.com/eLearning/courseDetail.aspx?courseId=26043&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Netcraft, Inc., Web Application Security Course&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://audited.netcraft.com/web-application-course&quot;&gt;http://audited.netcraft.com/web-application-course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Next Generation Security Software, Ltd., Security Training &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ngssoftware.com/consulting/training/&quot;&gt;http://www.ngssoftware.com/consulting/training/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;SecuRisk Solutions at&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securisksolutions.com/index.php/education/training/&quot;&gt;http://www.securisksolutions.com/index.php/education/training/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Security Innovation, Inc., Application Security Education &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securityinnovation.com/services/education/index.shtml&quot;&gt;http://www.securityinnovation.com/services/education/index.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The SANS Institute, Inc.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sans.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.sans.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/11_Academic_and_Commercial_Training_Samples_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="29556" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vendors</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/10_Vendors.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6fe526b2-39d1-4afc-b3c4-3c9a3168502d</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 08:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/10_Vendors_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object121_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Educators and trainers are often faced with a question from students regarding possible roles in an enterprise for software assurance professionals and their demand in the workforce. To facilitate such discussion, we have collected a few quotes from several training and credentialing entities below.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;SANS&lt;br/&gt;The SANS Software Security Institute (SSI) brings computer security training to developers, programmers, and application security professionals. They offer training for web application security and hacking defense, secure coding, software security testing, code review, PCI compliance, and language specific training for Java/JEE, .NET, C, and others. They also offer the Programmer/Developer Certification (GSSP) through their GIAC affiliate. They are also a source of free resources such as the Top 25 Most Dangerous Programming Errors. According to the System Administration, Audit, Network Security (SANS) Institute, one of the Top 20 coolest careers is Security-Savvy.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Developer:&lt;br/&gt;The security-savvy software developer leads all developers in the creation of secure software, implementing secure programming techniques that are free from logical design and technical implementation flaws.  This expert is ultimately responsible for ensuring customer software is free from vulnerabilities that can be exploited by an attacker.&lt;br/&gt;Why It's Cool&lt;br/&gt;    &amp;quot;You get to make something that actually runs and does something (and won't break under pressure).&amp;quot;&lt;br/&gt;    &amp;quot;These guys are the senior developers by virtue of their programming prowess.&amp;quot;&lt;br/&gt;How It Makes a Difference&lt;br/&gt;    &amp;quot;No security architecture or policy can compensate for poorly written, buggy, insecure software.  &lt;br/&gt;    If one pays the necessary attention to security when a product is initially developed, one doesn't &lt;br/&gt;    need to go back and add security later on.&amp;quot;&lt;br/&gt;    &amp;quot;This is where the rubber meets the road.  These are the people making a difference where &lt;br/&gt;    it really matters...in the software that runs the world.&amp;quot;&lt;br/&gt;How to Be Successful&lt;br/&gt;The role of security-savvy software developer is challenging and rewarding from multiple perspectives.  To be successful, you must understand a multitude of attack vectors used to exploit software to avoid the introduction of flaws.  This experience is also needed to leverage the same attack tools and techniques an adversary might use to exploit your software, and identify flaws to be addressed before product shipment. In a development role, your position will be vital to the company's success, including your ability to communicate the techniques used for secure software development to your peers.  This can be challenging, since few enjoy having their work criticized and flaws identified, but is a necessary component of an overall secure software strategy.  This role is critical beyond the success of the company to that of all the customers who implement your software.  Secure software development has a direct and undeniable impact on the ability of an organization to protect their systems and information assets, and you play a key role in that success.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;EC-Council&lt;br/&gt;The International Council of E-Commerce Consultants (EC-Council) is a member-based organization that certifies individuals in various e-business and information security skills. It is the owner and developer of the Certified Ethical Hacker (C|EH), Computer Hacking Forensics Investigator (C|HFI), and EC-Council Certified Security Analyst (E|CSA)/License Penetration Tester (L|PT) programs, and various others offered in over 60 countries around the globe. EC-Council is the creator of the Hacker Halted conference and workshop series and has established the EC-Council University based in New Mexico, which offers both bachelor's and master's degree programs. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Why Secure Programming&lt;br/&gt;    Most vulnerabilities stem from a relatively small number of common programming errors, according to the CERT/CC vulnerability reports. Understanding the security vulnerabilities in the application allows designers to create better security strategies for the application. The pervasiveness of easily remedied vulnerabilities indicates a lack of developer education on secure coding - VERACODE. Security quality of software ultimately determines the rate of data breaches and cyber threats that result in substantial losses to an organization.&lt;br/&gt;Reduce costs: The relative cost of fixing software defects after deployment is almost 15 times greater than detecting and eliminating them during development, according to a study by IBM's System Sciences Institute. &lt;br/&gt;Reduce serious risks: Despite having mission-critical applications accessible via their websites, many organizations are failing to provide sufficient resources to secure and protect Web applications important to their operations, according to the survey ‘State of Web Application &lt;br/&gt;Everyone benefits: Secure applications are more protected from media criticism, more attractive to users, and less expensive to fix and support.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;How to Be a Successful Secure Programmer?&lt;br/&gt;Understand the adversary: Just as a law officer uses “criminal profiling” to recognize the characteristics of unknown criminals, the successful secure programmer understands all the facets and the attack vectors a cyber-criminal may use to exploit the vulnerabilities in a software code. &lt;br/&gt;Avoid training gaps: Most application developers do not have any formal training in secure coding. Programming education curriculums most often do not include security issues. This results in developers who are either not aware of security issues or poorly skilled to overcome these issues. &lt;br/&gt;Invigorate security topics: The teaching methodology used by educational and training centers contributes to the erroneous perception of security topics as a dull subject.  Incorporating the development and procurement of resilient software and systems throughout the lifespan of a project relies on developer interest&lt;br/&gt;Work from a solid base: Define security and privacy requirements at the beginning and require team members to understand the software development lifecycle thoroughly. Details about recommended courses can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eccouncil.org/certification.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.eccouncil.org/certification.aspx&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(ISC)2&lt;br/&gt;International Information Systems Security Certification Consortium, Inc., (ISC)²® (pronounced &amp;quot;ISC-squared&amp;quot;) is a non-profit organization that educates and certifies information security professionals throughout their careers. The most widely known certification offered by the organization is the Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP). The Certified Secure Software Lifecycle Professional (CSSLP) Certification Program shows software lifecycle stakeholders how to implement security and how to glean security requirements, design, architect, test, and deploy secure software.  Attendees of the Software Assurance Forums and Working Group Sessions can receive &amp;quot;Continuing Professional Education” (CPE) credits.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The (ISC)2®  CSSLP® Curriculum  is a blueprint for establishing a security initiative in the software development lifecycle (SDLC).  It provides clear policies, procedures, and best practices for applying the NIST, PCI-DSS, and ISO 27xx standards.  Additionally, it incorporates best practices, policies, and procedures from Symantec, Cisco, Microsoft, SRA International, Xerox, EMC2, SAFEcode, SANS, RSA, ISSA, and The Department of Homeland Security. &lt;br/&gt;The comprehensive (ISC)2® CSSLP® CBK® Education Program covers the following domains:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Secure Software Concepts - security implications and methodologies within centralized and decentralized environments across the enterprise’s computer systems in software development.&lt;br/&gt;Secure Software Requirements - capturing security controls used during the requirements phase to integrate security within the process, to identify key security objectives, and to maximize software security while minimizing disruption to plans and schedules.&lt;br/&gt;Secure Software Design - translating security requirements into application design elements including documenting the elements of the software attack surfaces, conducting threat modeling, and defining any specific security criteria.&lt;br/&gt;Secure Software Implementation/Coding - involves the application of coding and testing standards, applying security testing tools including ‘fuzzing’, static-analysis code scanning tools, and conducting code reviews.&lt;br/&gt;Secure Software Testing - integrated QA testing for security functionality and resiliency to attack.&lt;br/&gt;Software Acceptance - security implications in the software acceptance phase including completion criteria, risk acceptance and documentation, Common Criteria and methods of independent testing.&lt;br/&gt;Software Deployment, Operations, Maintenance and Disposal - security issues around steady state operations and management of software. Security measures that must be taken when a product reaches its end of life.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;RESOURCES&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;System Administration, Audit, Network Security (SANS). Details about recommended courses can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sans.org/20coolestcareers/#job18&quot;&gt;http://www.sans.org/20coolestcareers/#job18&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;State of Web Application Security conducted by Ponemon Institute and sponsored by Imperva &amp;amp; WhiteHat Security, published April 26, 2010.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The (ISC)² Resource Guide for Information Security Professional, latest educational references, event listings, and leading industry organizations.https://&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isc2.org/resourceguide/&quot;&gt;www.isc2.org/resourceguide/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The CSSLP Education Program, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isc2.org/csslpedu&quot;&gt;www.isc2.org/csslpedu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/10_Vendors_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="36969" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workforce Credentials</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/9_Workforce_Credentials.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">077f6c17-a451-48c0-97f7-0f3630068e67</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 9 Apr 2012 08:31:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/9_Workforce_Credentials_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object122_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A list of Software Assurance certification and training opportunities&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;EC-Council&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eccouncil.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.eccouncil.org/certification.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Certified Secure Programmer (ECSP) (Technologies Covered: C/C++, Java, .Net, PHP, SQL )	&lt;br/&gt;Certified Secure Application Developer (CSAD)	&lt;br/&gt;Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH)	&lt;br/&gt;Licensed Penetration Tester (LPT)	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;GIAC - Global Information Assurance Certification&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.giac.org/certifications/&quot;&gt;http://www.giac.org/certifications/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;GIAC Secure Software Programmer - .NET (GSSP-NET)		&lt;br/&gt;GIAC Secure Software Programmer - Java (GSSP-JAVA)	&lt;br/&gt;GIAC Web Application Penetration Tester (GWAPT)	&lt;br/&gt;GIAC Certified Penetration Tester (GPEN)	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;IEEE Computer Society&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.computer.org/portal/&quot;&gt;http://www.computer.org/portal/web/certification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Certified Software Development Professional (CSDP)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(ISC)2&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isc2.org/csslp-certification.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.isc2.org/csslp-certification.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Certified Secure Software Lifecycle Professional (CSSLP)	</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/9_Workforce_Credentials_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="7461" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skills and Competency</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/8_Skills_and_Competency.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7eb73923-dbee-4ad0-9b05-8433dac37f1c</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 8 Apr 2012 09:00:28 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/8_Skills_and_Competency_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object084_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Credentials, Competencies and Skills by performance level&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Entry, Intermediate and Advanced&lt;br/&gt;Software Development&lt;br/&gt;Written &amp;amp; Oral Communication&lt;br/&gt;Creative Problem Solving&lt;br/&gt;Information Security/Assurance&lt;br/&gt;Critical Thinking and Analytical Skills	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Intermediate and Advanced&lt;br/&gt;Software Engineering&lt;br/&gt;Project/Program Management&lt;br/&gt;Leadership &amp;amp; People Management	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Entry: Associate’s Degree from an accredited program&lt;br/&gt;Intermediate: Bachelor’s Degree from an accredited program	&lt;br/&gt;Advanced: Master’s Degree from an accredited program plus 5 years’ experience&lt;br/&gt;Suggested Credentials in:&lt;br/&gt;    Computer science/engineering&lt;br/&gt;    Database/information management&lt;br/&gt;    Information assurance/security&lt;br/&gt;    Software assurance/security &lt;br/&gt;    Information systems management&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;OR &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Entry: 1 year experience in work directly related to: Secure network design, Database design and security, Secure coding and testing techniques &lt;br/&gt;Intermediate: 6 years experience, Possession and demonstrated application of relevant certifications (as determined by the department/agency)&lt;br/&gt;Advanced: Bachelor’s degree + 10 years relevant work experience and project management experience, Possession and demonstrated application of relevant certifications (as determined by the department/agency), with the addition of PMP&lt;br/&gt;Alternative experience/credentials:&lt;br/&gt;Information systems security certifications (e.g., ISC² CSSLP and CISSP, various SANS certs, EnCase Cybersecurity suite)&lt;br/&gt;Network engineering certifications (e.g., EnCase forensics suite, Cisco Certified Internetwork Expert (CCIE), GIAC Security Essentials Certification GSEC)&lt;br/&gt;Software/systems administration/engineering/development/ Database Management System (DBMS)certifications&lt;br/&gt;Relevant programming languages experience	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;RESOURCES&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Materials from the matrix project developed by Federal CIO Council’s IT Workforce Committee and Information Security and Identity Management Committee.&lt;br/&gt;Contacts: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/4&quot;&gt;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/5&quot;&gt;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/8_Skills_and_Competency_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="15826" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Describing SwA related Job Functions</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/7_Describing_SwA_related_Job_Functions.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9cfd191d-e25c-4a07-af25-a95d279cefe4</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 7 Apr 2012 11:51:47 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/7_Describing_SwA_related_Job_Functions_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object120_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The following role descriptions are from the matrix project developed by Federal CIO Council’s IT Workforce Committee and Information Security and Identity Management Committee.&lt;br/&gt;Contacts: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/4&quot;&gt;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/5&quot;&gt;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Cyber Software Assurance Developer/Integrator&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Experience with applying security activities within SDLC&lt;br/&gt;Experience with security, including CSSLP, CISSP and SANS secure programming assessments&lt;br/&gt;Experience with security standards, including SSE-CMM, NIST SPs, ISO 15408 &lt;br/&gt;Common Criteria, or client-specific software assurance guides. (Also see the section on “Standards of Practice”)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Assurance Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Provide technical leadership in all aspects of software assurance and computer systems engineering support.&lt;br/&gt;Lead and actively participate in the evaluation and analyses of activities related to all phases of the secure software life cycle from initial planning, requirements definition, design and development through integrated system testing and sustaining operations.&lt;br/&gt;Responsibilities will also include the support of a wide range of technical and programmatic activities for program offices, including leading the review and assessment of software system architecture; system requirements and their allocation to lower level specifications; design, code and test activities; trade studies; COTS/GOTS products; reuse software; test tools; simulators; software verification and validation (V&amp;amp;V); and system test and integration. Support independent review efforts in analyzing and assessing system software and related development and testing activities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Information Security Systems &amp;amp; Software Development Professional (ISSSDP)&lt;br/&gt;The Information Security Systems and Software Development Professional is responsible for secure design, development, testing, integration, implementation, sustainment, and/or documentation of software applications (web based and non-web) following formal secure systems development lifecycle processes and using security engineering principles.&lt;br/&gt;The following professional requirements form part of a broad Federal Government effort to identify and describe roles.  &lt;br/&gt;I: Entry level:&lt;br/&gt;Basic understanding of computer systems and related information security software and hardware components, network systems and databases, and information systems security safeguards&lt;br/&gt;Capable of articulating software/system abuse and misuse cases; understands practices and tools for mitigating exploitable software weaknesses&lt;br/&gt;Writes code in different programming languages (e.g., Java, C, C++)&lt;br/&gt;Integrates off-the-shelf products with information assurance safeguards (e.g., implementing network firewalls and routers)&lt;br/&gt;Participates in small teams performing software development and information security software-oriented tasks&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;II: Intermediate level:	&lt;br/&gt;Advanced understanding of information systems security, ethical hacking, multiple network analysis, configuration management, integration and deployment issues&lt;br/&gt;Designs secure software systems from requirements within the software development lifecycle; derives additional security requirements based on the deployment environment&lt;br/&gt;Communicates technical information to non-technical audiences and advises staff on information security issues and approaches&lt;br/&gt;Applies knowledge of information security aspects (e.g., coding, operating systems, programming languages, databases, federal and agency policies and procedures)&lt;br/&gt;Performs static and dynamic analysis to identify vulnerabilities in applications, across databases, networks, network-based environments, and operating systems, and directs remediation as appropriate&lt;br/&gt;Creates protocols, procedures, and guidelines to mitigate security risks&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;III: Advanced level:&lt;br/&gt;Expert understanding of information systems security,  ethical hacking, multiple network analysis, configuration management, integration and deployment issues&lt;br/&gt;Serves as senior advisor to the architectural design and development of enterprise-wide applications, systems, and services&lt;br/&gt;Serves as senior advisor to procurement and contract management in support of system and software acquisition &lt;br/&gt;Coordinates and collaborates across organizational and dept./agency lines; influences others to comply with security policies, standards, and best practices&lt;br/&gt;Integrates policies and procedures across government agencies; participates in the update of the agency’s knowledge of federal security policies, procedures, and guidelines&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Relevant Competency/Skills Sources (as determined by the department/agency):&lt;br/&gt;OPM GS-2200 Job Family Standard Competencies&lt;br/&gt;Clinger-Cohen Core Competencies with an emphasis on Technical, Desktop Technology Tools, and IT Security/Information Assurance competency areas&lt;br/&gt;Essential &lt;br/&gt;(EBK) for IT Security Professionals (e.g., DHS and DOE)&lt;br/&gt;NIST Special Publications (e.g., NIST SP 800-16, Revision 1, 800-37, 800-53, 800-53A) &lt;br/&gt;ODNI Cyber Subdirectory Competencies&lt;br/&gt;OPM’s Executive Core Qualifications (ECQs) (for SES positions)&lt;br/&gt;DHS SwA Communities and Forum (&lt;a href=&quot;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/&quot;&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/7_Describing_SwA_related_Job_Functions_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="7013" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standards of practice</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/6_Standards_of_practice.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8fc0cbc9-78b1-4d64-ba1d-f59b0e7809d9</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 6 Apr 2012 13:26:07 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/6_Standards_of_practice_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object123_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Domain-specific Software Assurance standards used in practice&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Assurance Process Reference Model (PRM)	&lt;br/&gt;Presentation: &lt;a href=&quot;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/downloads/ACSAC2010BartolMoss12-05-2010.pdf&quot;&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/downloads/ACSAC2010BartolMoss12-05-2010.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Self Assessment: &lt;a href=&quot;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/downloads/20100922_PRM_Practice_List_2page.pdf&quot;&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/downloads/20100922_PRM_Practice_List_2page.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Assurance PRM can be used to help organizations conduct a gap analysis of existing practices. The results of a gap analysis can be used to prioritize and track SwA implementation efforts. The Assurance PRM addresses assurance from executive to developer.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;BSIMM: The Building Security In Maturity Model&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bsimm2.com/&quot;&gt;http://bsimm.com&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;Pronounced “bee simm” was created by observing and analyzing real-world data from thirty leading software security initiatives. The BSIMM can help you determine how your organization compares to other real-world software security initiatives and what steps can be taken to make your approach more effective.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;CERT Resilience Management Model&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cert.org/resilience/rmm.html&quot;&gt;http://www.cert.org/resilience/rmm.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It has two primary objectives:&lt;br/&gt;1. Establish the convergence of operational risk and resilience management activities such as security, business continuity, and aspects of IT operations management into a single model.&lt;br/&gt;2. Apply a process improvement approach to operational resilience management through the definition and application of a capability level scale that expresses increasing levels of process improvement.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;CMMI-ACQ: Carnegie Mellon University (CMU)/Software Engineering Institute (SEI) Capability Maturity Model Integration (CMMI) for Acquisitions	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sei.cmu.edu/cmmi/index.cfm&quot;&gt;http://www.sei.cmu.edu/cmmi/index.cfm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Version 1.2. CMMI for Acquisition (CMMI-ACQ) is based on the CMMI Framework. CMMI for Acquisition (CMMI-ACQ) provides guidance to acquisition organizations for initiating and managing the acquisition of products and services. The model focuses on acquirer processes and integrates bodies of knowledge that are essential for successful acquisitions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;MISRA C: Motor Industry Software Reliability Association (MISRA)	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.misra.org.uk/&quot;&gt;http://www.misra.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;A software development standard for the C programming language developed by MISRA. Its aims are to facilitate code safety, portability and reliability in the context of embedded systems, specifically those systems programmed in ISO C. There is also a set of guidelines for MISRA C++.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;openSAMM: OWASP Open Software Assurance Maturity Model &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opensamm.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.opensamm.org&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;An open framework to help organizations formulate and implement a strategy for software security that is tailored to the specific risks facing the organization.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/6_Standards_of_practice_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="21925" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books for SwA education and training</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/5_Books_for_SwA_education_and_training.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b9ffe4d7-5154-4412-b6c1-2957d8d4b16d</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 5 Apr 2012 17:08:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/5_Books_for_SwA_education_and_training_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object083_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A list of Software Assurance focused books for use in education and training programs&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Attack Patterns, Reverse Engineering&lt;br/&gt;Implementation level issues	Exploiting Software: How to Break Code by Greg Hoglund and Gary McGraw, Addison Wesley, 2004	&lt;br/&gt;Understanding attack strategies to build better defenses. Case studies for class discussion. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.exploitingsoftware.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.exploitingsoftware.com&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Design Principles and Techniques	High-Assurance Design: Architecting Secure and Reliable Enterprise Applications, Clifford J. Berg, Addison-Wesley Professional 2005.	&lt;br/&gt;Basic principles and techniques that can be applied to the development of business applications. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Information Security	&lt;br/&gt;Building a Secure Computer System, Morrie Gasser, 1988&lt;br/&gt;Good reading for Information Security basics. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Principles and guidelines, Implementation level issues	&lt;br/&gt;24 Deadly Sins of Software Security: Programming Flaws and How to Fix Them Michael Howard, David LeBlanc, John Viega, McGraw-Hill Osborne Media, 2009	&lt;br/&gt;Identifies the most common design and coding errors, their fixes and avoidance strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Secure Coding in C and C++, Robert Seacord, Addison-Wesley Professional, 2005	&lt;br/&gt;Examples of secure code, insecure code, and exploits, implemented for Windows and Linux. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cert.org/books/secure-coding/&quot;&gt;http://www.cert.org/books/secure-coding/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Secure Programming for Linux and Unix HOWTO, David Wheeler, 2003	&lt;br/&gt;Unix systems-specific guidelines for C, C++, Java, Perl, PHP, Python, Tcl, and Ada95. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dwheeler.com/secure-programs/&quot;&gt;http://www.dwheeler.com/secure-programs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Building Secure Software: How to Avoid Security Problems the Right Way, John Viega and Gary McGraw, Addison Wesley, 2002	&lt;br/&gt;Software Assurance principles and guidelines and Implementation level issues Possible use as a textbook or additional reference material.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Assurance in SDLC	&lt;br/&gt;Secure and Resilient Software Development, Mark S. Merkow, Lakshmikanth Raghavan, Auerbach Publications, 2010	&lt;br/&gt;A practitioner’s perspective on enterprise assurance programs.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Security Engineering: A Guide for Project Managers, Julia Allen, Sean Barnum, Robert J. Ellison, Gary McGraw, Nancy R. Mead, Addison-Wesley, 2008 (ISBN 032150917X).	&lt;br/&gt;Software Security Engineering draws extensively on the systematic approach developed for the Build Security In (BSI) Web site. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.softwaresecurityengineering.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.softwaresecurityengineering.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Security Development Lifecycle: SDL: A Process for Developing Demonstrably More Secure Software, Michael Howard, Steve Lipner, Microsoft Press, 2006	&lt;br/&gt;Adaptation of Microsoft’s Security Development Lifecycle (SDL) with case-studies on several Microsoft products.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Security: Building Security In, Gary McGraw, Addison-Wesley Professional, 2006.	&lt;br/&gt;Introduction to Software Security Touchpoints during software development. Possible use as a textbook or additional reference material.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Secure Coding: Principles and Practices, Mark G. Graff and Kenneth R. van Wyk, O’Reilly, 2003	&lt;br/&gt;A practical approach to integrating SwA topics into the SDLC. Great for assignment of additional readings that complement classroom materials. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securecoding.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.securecoding.org&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Standards-based SwA Solutions	&lt;br/&gt;System Assurance: Beyond Detecting Vulnerabilities , Nikolai Mansourov and Djenana Campara, Morgan Kaufmann Publishers, Elsevier, 2011(ISBN: 978-0-12-381414-2	&lt;br/&gt;The Object Management Group (OMG) Software Assurance Ecosystem described in this book is a significant step towards collaborative cyber security automation; it offers a standards-based solution for building security and resilience in computer systems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Static Analysis	&lt;br/&gt;Secure Programming with Static Analysis, Brian Chess, Jacob West, Addison Wesley, 2007.	&lt;br/&gt;Detailed discussion of security issues in several open source applications; steps in the static analysis process.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/5_Books_for_SwA_education_and_training_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="29227" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools for hands-on exercises</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/4_Tools_for_hands-on_exercises.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">f661ad63-71cd-4305-8aa1-5bb0977a7e87</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 4 Apr 2012 18:49:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/4_Tools_for_hands-on_exercises_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object082_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tools and web resources that can be used in class to provide hands-on experience with SwA Concepts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;ArgoUML	&lt;br/&gt;ArgoUML is the leading open source UML modeling tool and includes support for all standard UML 1.4 diagrams. It runs on any Java platform.	&lt;br/&gt;Possible Use: Misuse cases, security focused UML class diagrams and other documentation for class assignments and projects. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;ASCE	&lt;br/&gt;ASCE supports the key assurance case notations: Goal Structuring Notation and Claims-Arguments-Evidence.  Academic license available upon request at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adelard.com/web/hnav/ASCE/index.html&quot;&gt;http://www.adelard.com/web/hnav/ASCE/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Assurance case documentation for class assignments and projects, Demonstration of worked examples used on real projects.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Anubis&lt;br/&gt;Anubis is a service for the dynamic analysis for unknown binaries, in particular Malware.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://anubis.iseclab.org/&quot;&gt;http://anubis.iseclab.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Malware analysis &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Burp Suite	&lt;br/&gt;Burp Suite is an integrated platform for attacking web applications. Located at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portswigger.net/suite/&quot;&gt;http://www.portswigger.net/suite/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Burp Suite allows the combination of manual and automated techniques to enumerate, analyze, scan, attack and exploit web applications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;CERT Secure Coding Standards	&lt;br/&gt;Secure coding standards for commonly used programming languages such as C, C++ and Java. Located at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.securecoding.cert.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.securecoding.cert.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Online reference; examples of coding do’s and dont’s.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;FindBugsTM	&lt;br/&gt;A program which uses static analysis to look for bugs in Java code at &lt;a href=&quot;http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;http://findbugs.sourceforge.net&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Scan java code repositories for bugs; Introduction to static code checking activities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Microsoft SDL Threat Modeling Tool	&lt;br/&gt;The Microsoft SDL Threat Modeling Tool allows software architects to identify and mitigate potential security issues early, when they are relatively easy and cost-effective to resolve. Located at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/security/sdl/getstarted/threatmodeling.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.microsoft.com/security/sdl/getstarted/threatmodeling.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Conduct student group workshops to discuss threats to various design alternatives, while suggesting possible mitigation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Olly Debug	&lt;br/&gt;OllyDbg is a 32-bit assembly level debugger for Microsoft Windows. Located at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ollydbg.de/&quot;&gt;www.ollydbg.de&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Emphasize binary code analysis and is particularly useful in cases where source is unavailable. Explain Buffer Overflows.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Pharos	&lt;br/&gt;Pharos is an open source proxy that traps all HTTP and HTTPS data between server and client, including cookies and form fields, which can be intercepted and modified. Located at &lt;a href=&quot;http://parosproxy.org/index.shtml&quot;&gt;http://parosproxy.org/index.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Pharos can be used as an introduction to web application security assessment. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;SAMATE Reference Dataset	&lt;br/&gt;The purpose of the SAMATE Reference Dataset (SRD) is to provide users, researchers, and software security assurance tool developers with a set of known security flaws.  This will allow end users to evaluate tools and tool developers to test their methods.  Located at &lt;a href=&quot;http://samate.nist.gov/index.php/Main_Page.html&quot;&gt;http://samate.nist.gov/index.php/Main_Page.html&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br/&gt;Possible use: A reference data set can be used in class to reflect upon known flaws in software.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;SDMetrics	&lt;br/&gt;Analyze the structural properties of UML models using object-oriented measures of design size, coupling, and complexity. Located at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sdmetrics.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.sdmetrics.com&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Examine object-oriented metrics and measures for design and source code artifacts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Splint	&lt;br/&gt;Splint is a tool for statically checking C programs for security vulnerabilities and coding mistakes. Located at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.splint.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.splint.org&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Static analysis code checking activities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Valgrind&lt;br/&gt;Valgrind is an instrumentation framework for building dynamic analysis tools. Located at &lt;a href=&quot;http://valgrind.org/&quot;&gt;http://valgrind.org&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Demonstrate dynamic analysis techniques to detect memory management and threading bugs, as well as detailed program profiling.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Vine	&lt;br/&gt;Provides an intermediate language that  x86 code can be translated to for Static analysis. Located at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitblaze.cs.berkeley.edu/vine.html&quot;&gt;http://bitblaze.cs.berkeley.edu/vine.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Possible use: Identify data flows analysis and conduct binary analysis.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Web Resources&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Google Code University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://google-gruyere.appspot.com/&quot;&gt;http://google-gruyere.appspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Web application exploits and defenses. Topics include cross-site scripting, cross site request forgery, AJAX vulnerabilities, denial of service, etc.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;OWASP Learning Environments	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.owasp.org/index.php/Phoenix/Tools&quot;&gt;http://www.owasp.org/index.php/Phoenix/Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Comprehensive collection of security tools, exploits, vulnerability scanners, defensive tools, application security.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;OWASP Web Goat	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_WebGoat_Project&quot;&gt;http://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_WebGoat_Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;WebGoat is a deliberately insecure J2EE web application maintained by OWASP designed to teach web application security lessons.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;OWASP Broken Web Applications Project	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_Broken_Web_Applications_Project&quot;&gt;http://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_Broken_Web_Applications_Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A collection of applications with known vulnerabilities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Assurance (SwA) Tools Overview 	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/swa_tools.html&quot;&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/swa_tools.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A collection of SwA tools inspired by the NIST Software Assurance Metrics And Tool Evaluation (SAMATE) project.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/4_Tools_for_hands-on_exercises_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="12383" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Injecting SwA topics in current programs</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/3_Injecting_SwA_topics_in_current_programs.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">404a2782-d77f-446a-9d59-d75f3e8a1fe2</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 3 Apr 2012 19:04:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/3_Injecting_SwA_topics_in_current_programs_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object081_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A enumeration of strategies to integrate software assurance topics into current education and training programs &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Publications on this topic&lt;br/&gt;Crosstalk March/April 2012, Carol A. Sledge, Engaging the Community: Strategies for Software Assurance Curricula Outreach.&lt;br/&gt;Engaging a knowledgeable team of educators to develop curricula, courses, and other materials for the discipline of software assurance will achieve more secure and better functioning software systems, regardless of their origins, application domain, or operational environments.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crosstalkonline.org/storage/issue-archives/2012/201203/201203-Sledge.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.crosstalkonline.org/storage/issue-archives/2012/201203/201203-Sledge.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Degree programs and specializations in SwA&lt;br/&gt;Reference curriculums available from the Software Engineering Institute, Carnegie Mellon University can be used as recommendations for designing Masters of Software Assurance degree program and undergraduate curriculum specialization in software assurance. These reference curriculums are available at&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://repository.cmu.edu/sei/3/&quot;&gt;http://repository.cmu.edu/sei/3/&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://repository.cmu.edu/sei/4/&quot;&gt;http://repository.cmu.edu/sei/4/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Graduate Certificates and Master Degree Concentrations at the Stevens Institute of Technology: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dc.stevens.edu/academic-programs/software-assurance/&quot;&gt;http://dc.stevens.edu/academic-programs/software-assurance/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Stand-alone Courses	&lt;br/&gt;New course offerings based on SwA knowledge areas complement existing Software Engineering courses. Examples: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.jmu.edu/sss&quot;&gt;http://www.cs.jmu.edu/sss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/display/sci/S08+15392+Secure+Programming&quot;&gt;https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/display/sci/S08+15392+Secure+Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Also: graduate-level Software Assurance courses that cover secure software engineering activities during the SDLC are offered at the University of North Carolina at Charlotte, and The University of Nebraska at Omaha.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Augmenting Existing Courses	&lt;br/&gt;The SwA CBK and State-of-the-Art reports are catalogs of secure software development practices, processes, and techniques that can be mapped to topics relevant to current curriculums. The identified gaps can then be filled using relevant materials.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Micro-Modules	&lt;br/&gt;Problem-based learning exercises, in class workshops, or short talks to inject topics such as Misuse Cases and Assurance Cases into existing software engineering or information security courses. Several other topics can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cert.org/mswa/lectures.html&quot;&gt;http://www.cert.org/mswa/lectures.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Capstone and Class Projects	&lt;br/&gt;Software Engineering capstone courses or class projects which can be geared towards a security critical domain such as designing a software system for the Department of Defense, Cyber-physical systems or for a Credit Card transaction processing company.  These domains will facilitate the exploration of security needs throughout the SDLC.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Online Courses	&lt;br/&gt;The Adaptive Cyber-Security Training Online (ACT-Online) courses are available on the TEEX Domestic Preparedness Campus. Ten courses address three discipline- specific tracks.  The targets are everyday non-technical computer users, technical IT professionals, business managers and professionals.  These courses are offered at no cost and students earn a DHS/FEMA Certificate of completion along with Continuing Education Units (CEU) at the completion of each course.        &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teexwmdcampus.com/user_defined_content.k2?contentID=6&quot;&gt;http://www.teexwmdcampus.com/user_defined_content.k2?contentID=6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The CERT Virtual Training Environment (VTE) combines the components of traditional classroom training with the convenience of web-based training.  Over 200 hours of course material focused around the technical, policy, and management implications of information security – including preparatory courses for commercial certifications, core skills courses, role-based courses for managers and technical staff, and vendor-developed courses. Open access is provided to individual DoD personnel (Active Duty, DoD Civilian and contractors) and members of the Federal Civilian Workforce through specific sponsorships from DISA, and DHS in conjunction with the Department of State Foreign Service Institute.  Sponsored accounts can be requested at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vte.cert.org/&quot;&gt;www.vte.cert.org&lt;/a&gt;.  Public access to many of the materials is provided through the VTE Library at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vte.cert.org/vteweb/Library/Library.aspx&quot;&gt;https://www.vte.cert.org/vteweb/Library/Library.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Semantic Templates	&lt;br/&gt;To cope with growing software complexity, programmers need better mental models to sense the possibility of a weakness. Current weakness enumerations and categorizations are not in a form that facilitates programmer understanding and recall. Semantic templates are being developed at the University of Nebraska, Omaha to improve programmer's ability to understand the CWEs related to the underlying software faults, weakness characteristics, resources/locations affected and the consequences for various egregious weakness types. &lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/st/&quot;&gt;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/st/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Fault Patterns	&lt;br/&gt;Software Fault Patterns (SFP) provide a generalized description of an identifiable family of computations that lead to weaknesses. These patterns are aligned with CWEs and are fully identifiable in code. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/presentations_091211/Mansourov-SoftwareFaultPatterns.pdf&quot;&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/swa/presentations_091211/Mansourov-SoftwareFaultPatterns.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Awareness and Self-study Resources	&lt;br/&gt;SAFECode: Software Assurance Forum for Excellence in Code. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.safecode.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.safecode.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fundamental Practices for Secure Software Development&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Dev_Practices1108.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Dev_Practices1108.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Security Engineering Training&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Training0409.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Training0409.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Assurance: An Overview of Current Industry Best Practices&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_BestPractices0208.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_BestPractices0208.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Framework for Software Supply Chain Integrity&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Supply_Chain0709.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Supply_Chain0709.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Integrity Controls: An Assurance-Based Approach to Minimizing Risks in the Software Supply Chain. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Software_Integrity_Controls0610.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.safecode.org/publications/SAFECode_Software_Integrity_Controls0610.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rugged Software&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ruggedsoftware.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.ruggedsoftware.org&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Podcasts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cigital.com/silverbullet/&quot;&gt;http://www.cigital.com/silverbullet/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Community Support	&lt;br/&gt;LinkedIn SwA Education Discussion Group&lt;br/&gt;Nancy Mead, SwA Curriculum Team lead&lt;br/&gt;The objective of the SwA Curriculum Development Team in establishing this group is to provide a venue for dialog about software assurance education. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/groups?mostPopular=&amp;gid=3430456&quot;&gt;http://www.linkedin.com/groups?mostPopular=&amp;amp;gid=3430456&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Assurance Mobile Instructional (device) SAMI&lt;br/&gt;Dan Shoemaker, University of Detroit Mercy&lt;br/&gt;A catalogue of available software assurance materials that are packaged and delivered using an iPad based instruction medium for educators.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Credentialing&lt;br/&gt;Several certification options are now available to suit the needs of specific job functions required in an enterprise. More information can be found in the Workforce Credentials article.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/3_Injecting_SwA_topics_in_current_programs_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="20857" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workforce Development and Improvement</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/2_Workforce_Development_and_Improvement.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">e4be1d0b-f07c-4162-a1d6-f8072b324b49</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 2 Apr 2012 20:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/2_Workforce_Development_and_Improvement_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object080_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;These resources have been developed to facilitate the development of roles and responsibilities of individuals performing software and information assurance related job functions. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;DoD 8570.01-M	Information Assurance Workforce Improvement Program. Assistant Secretary of Defense for Networks and Information Integration/Department of Defense Chief Information Officer. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dtic.mil/whs/directives/corres/pdf/857001m.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.dtic.mil/whs/directives/corres/pdf/857001m.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Provides guidance and procedures for the training, certification, and management of the DoD workforce conducting Information Assurance (IA) functions in assigned duty positions. Last update: Incorporating Change 2, April 20, 2010.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;IT Security Essential Body of Knowledge (EBK): A Competency and Functional Framework for IT Security Workforce Development. DHS US-CERT&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.us-cert.gov/ITSecurityEBK/&quot;&gt;http://www.us-cert.gov/ITSecurityEBK/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Characterizes the IT security workforce and provides a national baseline of essential knowledge and skills that IT security practitioners should have in order to perform specific roles and responsibilities. Last updated September 2008.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Information Security Workforce Development Matrix Project – Information Security Systems and Software Development Professional Role, Developed by Federal CIO Council’s IT Workforce Committee and Information Security and Identity Management Committee.&lt;br/&gt;Contacts: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/4&quot;&gt;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/5&quot;&gt;http://www.cio.gov/committees.cfm/csec/3/cid/5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;This project produces role-based information security workforce development matrices. The matrices are one-page dashboards intended to establish a baseline across the Federal Government for staff engaged in information security work. This initiative provides a government-wide perspective on common information security roles. The ISS&amp;amp;SDP is one of 11 roles that have been identified to date. Each matrix contains a uniform framework, by performance level, describing the recommended competencies/skills, education, experience, credentials, and training for a particular role. The matrices provide guidance for federal agencies and do not replace OPM basic qualifications.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/2_Workforce_Development_and_Improvement_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="32354" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key SwA knowledge Areas &amp; Efforts</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/1_Key_SwA_knowledge_Areas_%26_Efforts.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">41dedf0c-542a-4719-b4b0-5d62d34d14bd</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Apr 2012 21:10:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/1_Key_SwA_knowledge_Areas_%26_Efforts_files/droppedImage.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object003_1.png&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:230px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The chart summarizes available workforce training materials and shows where to look for resources in SwA-related fields.</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/4/1_Key_SwA_knowledge_Areas_%26_Efforts_files/droppedImage.png" length="118263" type="image/png"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum and Training Guides</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/3/31_Curriculum_and_Training_Guides.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">df3536b7-92c7-4cf1-a7c8-147c362f02fd</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 21:22:07 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/3/31_Curriculum_and_Training_Guides_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object124_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;These resources have been developed to facilitate the integration of software assurance topics in current educational program and training.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;SwA CBK and Organization of Principles and Guidelines	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Towards an Organization for Software System Security Principles and Guidelines. Version 1.0, Samuel T.  Redwine, Jr., &lt;a href=&quot;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/bsi/dhs/927-BSI.html&quot;&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/bsi/dhs/927-BSI.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Provides an extensive set of software system security principles and guidelines organized in a logical, in-depth fashion. Last updated February 2008.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Assurance Body of Knowledge. Version 1.2, Samuel T. Redwine, Jr. (Editor), DHS, &lt;a href=&quot;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/bsi/dhs/927-BSI.html&quot;&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/bsi/dhs/927-BSI.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Provides a comprehensive set of principles and guidelines from the disciplines of software engineering, systems engineering, information system, computer science, safety, security, testing, information &lt;br/&gt;assurance, and project management. Last updated October 2007.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;SwA Curriculum Project	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Volume I: Master of Software Assurance Reference Curriculum. Mead, Nancy R. et al. SEI/CMU. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cert.org/mswa/&quot;&gt;http://www.cert.org/mswa/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cert.org/podcast/show/20101026mead.html&quot;&gt;http://www.cert.org/podcast/show/20101026mead.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Offers a core body of knowledge from which to create a master’s level degree program in software assurance, as a standalone offering and as a track within existing software engineering and computer science master’s degree programs. Last updated 2010.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Volume II: Undergraduate Course Outlines. Mead, Nancy R. et al. SEI/CMU. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cert.org/mswa/&quot;&gt;http://www.cert.org/mswa/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Focuses on an undergraduate curriculum specialization for software assurance. Intended to provide students with fundamental skills for either entering the field directly or continuing with graduate level education. Last updated 2010.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Volume III: Master of Software Assurance Course Syllabi. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cert.org/archive/pdf/11tr013.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.cert.org/archive/pdf/11tr013.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The syllabi support the development of a set of courses to be used in a master of software assurance curriculum. In addition to application in a standard university program, these syllabi may also be useful for educators developing courses for industry practitioners. Last updated 2011&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Volume IV: Community College Education. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cert.org/archive/pdf/11tr017.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.cert.org/archive/pdf/11tr017.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The community college courses are intended to provide students with fundamental skills for continuing with graduate-level education or to provide supplementary education for students with prior undergraduate technical degrees who wish to become more specialized in software assurance. Last updated 2011&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Security Assurance SOAR	&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Enhancing the Development Life Cycle to Produce Secure Software: A Reference Guidebook on Software Assurance. Goertzel, Karen et al.  For DHS and DTIC, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedacs.com/techs/enhanced_life_cycles/&quot;&gt;https://www.thedacs.com/techs/enhanced_life_cycles/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Complements the Software Security Assurance: A State-of-the-Art Report with further details. Last updated October 2008.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software Security Assurance: A State-of-the-Art Report. Goertzel, Karen Mercedes, et al, IATAC of the DTIC. &lt;a href=&quot;http://iac.dtic.mil/iatac/download/security.pdf&quot;&gt;http://iac.dtic.mil/iatac/download/security.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Identifies the current state of the art in software security assurance. Last updated July 2007.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/3/31_Curriculum_and_Training_Guides_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="14898" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Case for SwA Education</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/3/30_The_Case_for_SwA_Education.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4cb047f5-24f5-4a09-94f0-73af35d4de80</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 22:05:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/3/30_The_Case_for_SwA_Education_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object057_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Software size and complexity obscures intent and precludes exhaustive testing. Outsourcing and use of un-vetted software supply chains increases risk. Attack sophistication now eases exploitation. These factors contribute to the increase of risks to software-enabled capabilities and the threat of asymmetric attack.  A broad range of stakeholders now need confidence that the software which enables their core business operations can be trusted to perform (even under attempted exploitation).  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In their report to the President, in the chapter entitled “Software Is a Major Vulnerability”, the President’s Information Technology Advisory Committee (PITAC) summed up the problem of non-secure software concisely and accurately:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“Network connectivity provides “door-to-door” transportation for attackers, but vulnerabilities in the software residing in computers substantially compound the cyber security problem.  As the PITAC noted in a 1999 report, the software development methods that have been the norm fail to provide the high quality, reliable, and secure software that the Information Technology infrastructure requires.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software development is not yet a science or a rigorous discipline, and the development process by and large is not controlled to minimize the vulnerabilities that attackers exploit.  Today, as with cancer, vulnerable software can be invaded and modified to cause damage to previously healthy software, and infected software can replicate itself and be carried across networks to cause damage in other systems.  Like cancer, these damaging processes may be invisible to the lay person even though experts recognize that their threat is growing.  And as in cancer, both preventive actions and research are critical, the former to minimize damage today and the latter to establish a foundation of knowledge and capabilities that will assist the cyber security professionals of tomorrow reduce risk and minimize damage for the long term.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Vulnerabilities in software that are introduced by mistake or poor practices are a serious problem today.  In the future, the Nation may face an even more challenging problem as adversaries - both foreign and domestic – become increasingly sophisticated in their ability to insert malicious code into critical software.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It is clear that to produce, acquire, and sustain secure software, a framework that identifies workforce needs for competencies, leverages sound practices, and guides curriculum development for education and training relevant to software assurance is inevitable.  Because software quality assurance and software engineering have evolved bodies of knowledge that do not explicitly address security as a quality attribute, a workforce education and training framework must also identify the integration point of secure software development techniques and practices in the existing programs nationwide.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;RESOURCES&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;President’s Information Technology Advisory Committee (PITAC) Report, Cyber Security: A Crisis of Prioritization, February 2005</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/3/30_The_Case_for_SwA_Education_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="19224" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Need for Software Assurance</title>
      <link>http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/3/29_The_Need_for_Software_Assurance.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1c50bac8-d6be-4402-b9a6-f6fd83badc6b</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 23:26:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/3/29_The_Need_for_Software_Assurance_files/droppedImage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Media/object047_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:254px; height:135px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Current events related to cybersecurity encourage a fundamental shift in the way we think about educating and training a workforce prepared to address security issues in all phases of a software system.  Software assurance education and training touches on software engineering (including its many sub-disciplines), systems engineering, project management, and other disciplines (shown in chart Key SwA Knowledge Areas and Efforts, page 6). The goal is to fit the workforce with the ability to identify and acquire the competencies associated with secure software.  The primary audiences for this pocket guide are educators and trainers who can use this guide to identify resources to supplement their efforts as well as to identify strategies to inject software assurance related topics in the existing education and training programs. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The objective of software assurance is to ensure that the processes, procedures, and products used to produce and sustain the software conform to all specified requirements and standards. Software assurance in its broader sense refers to the assurance of any required property of software.  However, in the context of this pocket guide, software assurance is concerned with assuring the security of software.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Building secure software requires a workforce that understands the processes and technologies that provide the basis for belief that software will consistently exhibit all properties required to ensure that the software will operate as expected, despite the presence of faults introduced by a malicious adversary.  The Ware Report (1969) identified that:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“Probably the most serious risk in system software is incomplete design, in the sense that inadvertent loopholes exist in the protective barriers and have not been foreseen by the designers.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Later the Anderson Report (1972) clearly established the technical problem to be solved as that of:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“…determining what constitutes an appropriate defense against malicious attack, and then developing hardware and software with the defensive mechanisms built in.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Nearly forty years after, as we find ourselves in the midst of a highly interconnected cyber infrastructure, the need for a workforce with better skills to build security in cannot be emphasized enough.  The objective is to enable a workforce competent in managing, designing, implementing and evaluating systems that can enforce security policies and fulfill security expectations.  This workforce should be able to develop a well-reasoned and audit-able basis for believing that the software will function as expected, i.e. have justifiable arguments to questions such as: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;How secure is your software? &lt;br/&gt;What is it secure against?&lt;br/&gt;How does it achieve its security goals?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This Pocket Guide presents a general map of the areas of knowledge to cover in order to build security into software.  The guide organizes the resources available for SwA outreach by avenue of approach:  student curricula, workforce improvement, injection of subject-area material into related disciplines, credentialing, awareness, and independent study.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;RESOURCES&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Willis Ware, Security Controls for Computer Systems (U): Report of Defense Science Board Task Force on Computer Security; Rand Report R609-1, The RAND Corporation, Santa Monica, CA, Feb. 1970.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;James P. Anderson, Computer Security Technology Planning Study, ESD-TR-73-51, ESD/AFSC, Hanscom AFB, Bedford, MA 01731, Oct. 1972&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://faculty.ist.unomaha.edu/rgandhi/swa/SwAPGWET/Topics/Entries/2012/3/29_The_Need_for_Software_Assurance_files/droppedImage.jpg" length="18261" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
