<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="B7AB1949-CE90-4289-A32D-3049187EF0A7">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120524" date="2012-05-25 01:55:29 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Curriculum and Training Guides</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="31_Curriculum_and_Training_Guides_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="395px" height="210px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>These resources have been developed to facilitate the integration of software assurance topics in current educational program and training.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;SwA CBK and Organization of Principles and Guidelines	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;Towards an Organization for Software System Security Principles and Guidelines. Version 1.0, Samuel T.  Redwine, Jr., &lt;a href="https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/bsi/dhs/927-BSI.html"&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/bsi/dhs/927-BSI.html&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Provides an extensive set of software system security principles and guidelines organized in a logical, in-depth fashion. Last updated February 2008.&#xD;&#xD;Software Assurance Body of Knowledge. Version 1.2, Samuel T. Redwine, Jr. (Editor), DHS, &lt;a href="https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/bsi/dhs/927-BSI.html"&gt;https://buildsecurityin.us-cert.gov/bsi/dhs/927-BSI.html&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Provides a comprehensive set of principles and guidelines from the disciplines of software engineering, systems engineering, information system, computer science, safety, security, testing, information &#xD;assurance, and project management. Last updated October 2007.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;SwA Curriculum Project	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;Volume I: Master of Software Assurance Reference Curriculum. Mead, Nancy R. et al. SEI/CMU. &lt;a href="http://www.cert.org/mswa/"&gt;http://www.cert.org/mswa/&lt;/a&gt; &#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.cert.org/podcast/show/20101026mead.html"&gt;http://www.cert.org/podcast/show/20101026mead.html&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Offers a core body of knowledge from which to create a master&#x2019;s level degree program in software assurance, as a standalone offering and as a track within existing software engineering and computer science master&#x2019;s degree programs. Last updated 2010.&#xD;&#xD;Volume II: Undergraduate Course Outlines. Mead, Nancy R. et al. SEI/CMU. &#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.cert.org/mswa/"&gt;http://www.cert.org/mswa/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Focuses on an undergraduate curriculum specialization for software assurance. Intended to provide students with fundamental skills for either entering the field directly or continuing with graduate level education. Last updated 2010.&#xD;&#xD;Volume III: Master of Software Assurance Course Syllabi. &#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.cert.org/archive/pdf/11tr013.pdf"&gt;http://www.cert.org/archive/pdf/11tr013.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &#xD;The syllabi support the development of a set of courses to be used in a master of software assurance curriculum. In addition to application in a standard university program, these syllabi may also be useful for educators developing courses for industry practitioners. Last updated 2011&#xD;&#xD;Volume IV: Community College Education. &#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.cert.org/archive/pdf/11tr017.pdf"&gt;http://www.cert.org/archive/pdf/11tr017.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &#xD;The community college courses are intended to provide students with fundamental skills for continuing with graduate-level education or to provide supplementary education for students with prior undergraduate technical degrees who wish to become more specialized in software assurance. Last updated 2011&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Software Security Assurance SOAR	&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Enhancing the Development Life Cycle to Produce Secure Software: A Reference Guidebook on Software Assurance. Goertzel, Karen et al.  For DHS and DTIC, &lt;a href="https://www.thedacs.com/techs/enhanced_life_cycles/"&gt;https://www.thedacs.com/techs/enhanced_life_cycles/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Complements the Software Security Assurance: A State-of-the-Art Report with further details. Last updated October 2008.&#xD;&#xD;Software Security Assurance: A State-of-the-Art Report. Goertzel, Karen Mercedes, et al, IATAC of the DTIC. &lt;a href="http://iac.dtic.mil/iatac/download/security.pdf"&gt;http://iac.dtic.mil/iatac/download/security.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;Identifies the current state of the art in software security assurance. Last updated July 2007.&#xD; &#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Curriculum and Training Guides</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;3/31/12&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
